I'm so interested in robots and how
Ita Im 'interested in robots et quam
they're being used in things like like
quod ipsi erant 'usus est in rebus quasi, sicut
medical and education and all of the
et medicinae educationem et in omnes
neat things that robots can be used for
quae commode adhiberi potest robots
these days robot a robot lab is a leader
hi dies a robot robot Lab est princeps
in inspiring the imagination of kids of
haedos autem cogitatio in animum addens
all ages they're building 21st century
ipsi erant 'omnia saecula saeculorum aedificationem Saeculum 21
skills like programming computational
artes quasi programming computational
thinking and they use robots to do it
Utuntur quidem cogitant robots
please help me welcome a lad in bar he's
placere adiuva me receperint puer unus talea per se scriptor
the CEO of robot lab hey lad nice to see
CEO of the lad robot Lab heus nice videre
ya hey thanks for having me and I see
Puer heu me, et agens et habens video
you've brought some friends I see now
quosdam amicos te duxit modo video
yeah
yeah
well it's so great to have you on the
tam multa bene in vos
show and we're looking forward to
et ostendam erant 'vultus deinceps ad
learning all about what you're doing
discere quae agis
with robots in the education sector
cum robots sunt in educationem sector
first of all you know robots have come a
Primum scire veni robots
long way in the nine years that you've
dum modo in novem annis, ut youve '
been working with robot lab can you tell
Lab potest opus esse, cum robot amen dico vobis:
us a little bit about the progression
nos paululum de progressum
right off the bat you know what have you
tu scis quod habent ius off vespertilionem
seen that is the biggest kind of change
videtur, quod genere mutatio est maximus
as far as driving the robot industry I
quatenus fieri pellendo finibus robot industria me
think the main trend that we are seeing
Puto quod trend pelagus prae oculis habes
is that robots are becoming less geeky
diminuerentur, quod robots geeky
you know if you're looking like 10 or 20
Si tu scis te erant 'vultus ut X aut XX
years back robots were basically kids
robots sunt basically haedos retro annis
that you need to solder and work on
quod et operatur in vobis opus solidabis
electronics and you know why are things
electronics et scire quid sint haec
and connect it and build your own thing
et coniungere tua et aedificare illud
right and in the recent years we are
et in dextera Superioribus annis sumus
seeing you know they move towards what
cum ipsi scitis quod ad movere
we call today smart
hodie vocamus dolor
toys which are you know preassembled
nugas qui estis vos scitis Preassembled
products that are capable of doing many
quod multa possunt fructus
many things by themselves like the non
multa a se tamquam non
robot that we have over here and they
habemus hic et robot
can be extended that can be programmed
qui possit extendi programma
to do many other things so I think this
et plura facere puto
is the main shift that we see and on top
est pelagus subcinctus quae videtis et supra,
of course you know the direct with our
Nescio sane in directum nostra
staff like you know better CPU more ya
sicut melius nosti virgam magis Puer CPU
know memory and so on but the fact that
ita tamen quod memoria teneo
you know you don't need to solder them
tu scis te non postulo solidabis
you don't need to build them yourself
non opus est te ipsum facere eis
open the robotics were to you know way
robotics essent aperire viam scitis
more people way more industry than what
ita multo magis industria hominum quam quod
it was just a few years ago and now your
esset iustus paucis abhinc annis, et nunc vestris
focus at robot lab is primarily on the
ad focus principaliter in robot est lab
education sector
educationem sector
in that and like how how do you bring
ut quemadmodum in illa, et quomodo tecum attuleris
robots into classrooms and what is the
et quod robots sunt in classrooms
incentive to really to do that like why
quod maxime ad rem facere, ut quasi
like why bots yeah so with the cool it's
memini sicut automata quare sic frigida est
funny because the big why here is
quare hic, quia magnus ridiculam
actually coming from the students
alumni ex actually
imagine you know where you know typical
imaginari unde scis tu scis typical
teenager right sitting in a math
teenager dextera sedens in math
classroom yeah the teacher is talking
yeah magister loquitur sit Curabitur aliquet ultricies
about quadratic equations
circa aequationem quadraticam
what does he have above his head why why
quod supra caput propter quid
do I need to learn them it's not
non opus est ut suus 'non discere eorum
interesting I'll never use it in my life
Et interesting utor is nunquam in vita mea
right this is you know the main things
Ius id praecipue nosti
that happen here
hic aguntur
they just keep asking yourself why why
ut eos mox ut quid te petis, quod
why why do I need to do all of this
quid faciam quod facio necesse est ut omnia haec
especially today that you know they have
praesertim hodie, ut scitis habent
access to data on their smartphone they
Mauris ut accessum eorum notitia
can you know ask Google whatever they
Quaero Google quicquid cognosces
want and we'll get an answer why do I
quod youll 'adepto responsum volo et non faciunt
need to learn that
necesse est ut discat
why don't we develop equations and all
cur non omnibus aequationibus ut develop
of that so what we are showing them is
Quid est enim quod ostenso
we're helping them understand why they
quid intelligis quod nos auxilium eorum
need to learn that and we do that with
necesse est, ut discendum est et facere
robots now robots I mean as you can see
robots autem non intelliguntur, ut videre potes robots
here they are very alive they are very
Hic sunt vivi sint
visual and they can help the students
et visual auxilium alumni potest,
understand these kind of subjects so in
Itaque huiusmodi rebus intellegat
one of our programs for example the
qui nostra consilia ad exemplum
their students make the robot dance now
Nunc discipuli sui faciunt in choro robot
making a robot dance it's something you
quid suus 'vestri faciens in choro robot
know noble of fun for itself but if you
sciant se nobilissimosque fun si
really want to make the robot move let's
facere moventur ad robot vere volo ut lets '
say there is a very popular dance in
dico enim est chorus in ipsis popularibus
schools now raise the roof right so it
Nunc ergo recte attollere tectis scholis
won't you know to make the robot raise
ut suscitet te non robot
the roof you don't have to be able to
non potest esse in tecto
control each one of the joints and set
et posuit control cuiusque unius compagibus
the angle okay control you know the
bene tibi erit et angulus potestate cognoscere
motion of the robot and what we do is we
aut si quid est quod in robot motus est nobis
show the students that you actually do
alumni ostendere quod non eris aut subiciemur
that using math okay so you program that
ut usura vestri math progressio tam bene quam
using math to actually create the
per quod actu creare math
equations that make you know mirror the
scio te in speculum translucet aequationes,
motion perfectly smooth so they applied
Motus igitur plana applicuerunt
the math into something that they care
in math in aliquid quod pertinet,
about that they really you know want to
ut qui vere volo ut scitis
make you know move and interacting and
et ostendam tibi mutuo movere
dance that's that's the you know the
id, quod chorus est non cognoscere
biggest incentive here right so I'll add
maximus hie dat stimulos addere ius et Faciam
when you talk about mathematics for
Cum enim mathematica loqui
example like how does how does a student
sicut exempli gratia, quam modo non habet discipulus
learn to program one of these robots is
discere ad propositum una harum sit robots
it its own language or talking just
hoc modo loquentes linguis scriptas suum
learning Pro
pro doctrina
ramming in general so we have to you
nam cum rostro percussisset generatim ita nos habemus ad vos
know two ways or two areas that we you
duo modi scitis neque duas areas ut es
know apply this robot that the first one
scio quod primum applicare robot
is using obviously computer science so
per hoc computatrum scientia manifesto et
we want the students to be able to
si vis alumni ad esse potest
program to study programming and they do
studere et facere progressio programming
that by working on these robots either
neque id obscure faciens haec robots
from a drag-and-drop interface very easy
et traxit ex interface facilisis dui,
you know beginners can like in no time
scire potest beginners in nullo tempore similis tibi
can just like you know drive pretty fine
quia sicut non es pulchellus bene agitare
if it is right okay does connect them
si bene facit est coniungere eos
together and boom the robot just that
simul et per robot BUTIO iustus est
can stand up and talk and interact with
non potest stare sursum, et quod loqui penitus per
you but the robot also supports Python
sed etiam non sustinet robot pythonem
and Java and C++ so you can take it you
et C ++ ut possideatis eam Java
know further along and you can create
per amplius poteris cognoscere et creare
you know whatever you want
Vis scire quid
we have students created you know
Scitis enim habemus alumni creata est
Twitter accounts for for these robots
Propterea haec robots pro Twitter
and the robot actually tweeting and
et actually robot et tweeting
sending pictures and messages and
missisque nuntiis pictures
everything so I take it then just you
omne igitur iustum non est ut áuferant eam
know these are not powered by Microsoft
praescientes custodite ne powered by Microsoft
no because we've had bad experiences
quia non habebat experientiam mali
there yes version of Debian that runs on
Etiam ibi qui decurrit ad versionem debian
that oh yeah so we are safe here I mean
yeah, quod utinam sic intelliguntur hic salvus esse
very cool
valde frigus
so I mean truly the teachers are
ut sit vere doctores
teaching like I'm like multi-layered
sicut doctrina non sum sicut multi-stratoso
lessons if they're teaching sort of
Lectiones si doces generis
computer programming and then also
tum etiam programmandi
mathematics or physics exactly this is
haec est mathematica, vel prorsus Physicis
actually the second type of you know use
secundum genus usum esse scire te
case which is we don't want you know the
volo autem vos scire quod si non est,
teachers to you know teach programming
Cum magistris scholarum, docebit vos scitis programming
in every class when they're teaching
cum in omni genere doces
math it should be math right I mean
math iure mathematica sit id
that's a main focus of the lesson
quod in principalis focus in disciplina
sure so what we are doing we are
quid agimus nos quidem
allowing the students to control these
Ad imperium hisce alumni permittens
robots directly from a web browser so
ita e telam pasco robots
they don't need any coding or
non opus est, aut ulla coding
programming or anything like that they
seu quod simile vestibulum
just make the robot you know you know
in tantum ut scis tu scis robot
execute the equations or run you know
aequationes currere faciam vobis
what we want them to do study at that
quid vis ut faciam studio eo
lesson so hasn't it has now been
nunc autem iam non ut praecipiam
basically you know just to understand
plerumque tantum intelligere cognoscetis
the inner workings has it been built as
id est, ut penitus ex integro fabricatis
an educational tool so that it's easier
suus 'facillimus ut instrumentum an educational
for teachers to use to teach these
ut hi magistri docere
lessons whether they be mathematics or
sive lectiones aut mathematicis
science or programming I know the now
Nunc scio ex scientia seu programming
was created as a novelty robot that
quia creatus est ut tanta novitas robot
do many things it's a platform and there
et multa facitis illud suggestum est
are many uses for that I mean we've seen
quae sunt usus intelliguntur non vidi;
people using it you know all the way
homines enim per omnem viam scitis
from you know retail environments really
vere quia a te retail ferendum
to helping patients you know after after
ut auxilio postquam scis cum aegris
surgeries and so on recovering you know
et recipiendae surgeries in vos scitis
faster and so on so it's a platform that
ocius illud suggestum est et ita
can do many many things it's totally
Multi multa potest facere est prorsus
open it's not limited to anything we
suus 'limited to open nec quicquam nos
found the niche in education because a
et inventum est quod iussisti, in educatione
few things first of all they're cute
pauca prius haerent bellus
darn adorable except you give me the
Nisi mihi veneranda darn
evil eye right now so they are here then
nunc autem oculus ita adsunt
and you know this cuteness factor you
et non factor scitote cuteness
know removes a lot of barriers so it's
quia ita est aufert multus of barriers
not like an industrial robotic arm that
cīvitās industrialis est brachium illud non placet robotic
can leave the I don't know the three
Consequat ut lacus tempus a nescio trium
thousand pound car you just like and you
mnarum mille, currus iustus amo vestri et vos
know when you kill you it's something
scio te interficiemus te, quando aliquid suus '
that you know won't harm you and because
ut noceat te quoniam non scitis
of that and because of the you know form
ut scias quia Domini est forma
factor it's actually the I mean kids are
factor suus 'vere non est medium haedos
really you know want to work with that
vere scio vos volo ut opus in eo
the second thing is that robots are not
secundum est quod robots sunt
judgmental and this is a very powerful
idque plurimum iudicium
you know thing in education sure a lot
scis certe multam educationem rem
of times when you know think about
temporum de cognitis
students again when they make a mistake
Errant etiam cum discipulis
you know feature the parents who ever
scio te quis umquam parentibus feature
just like them you can do better right I
sicut eis melius facere ius poteris tibi
mean it's just like driving we are like
sit suus 'iustus quasi incessus quasi non sint
very judgmental and you know many times
ipsi scitis iudicium saepe
kids just like you know the cringe ins
haedos sicut scitis in ius cringe
and I don't want even to try again
et convertimini ad nolo
because I'll fail right and I don't want
quod youll 'volo et non deficient recta
the same negative experience but if the
sed si eiusdem usum negans
robot made a mistake let's say I wanted
robot fecit errorem lets 'narro EGO volo
the robot to raise the roof that's what
Id attollere tectis robot
we said then we didn't get to raise the
et nos dicti sumus, et non pervenit ad sollicitandos pastores praemisit
roof we got like crazy dance sure yeah
ut certus got nos rabidus tectum chorus yeah
yeah that's really heat so you know I
yeah quod suus 'vere calor est et scitis
blame the wrong but the robot won't be
culpare nefas est autem robot non erit
angry at me I'll try harder because I
durius agam mihi indignamini quia
wanted the little guy to do you know
scis facere voluisse inquiens
what I want so cool because for
propter frigus, quod volo, sic pro
non-judgemental they are you know a
scitis a non-judgmental non sunt
great tool that empower the learning
magnae eruditionis instrumentum quod talem
students it's it's really neat to me
alumni suus 'suus' vere tersus ad me
that you've learned that about the
quod didici te, ut de
robots because like it takes having that
quia sicut in illa accipit robots
experience and realizing that hey
heu experientia situs,
they're not gonna write be hard on the
illi non es agnus dei esse difficile scribere in
kid exactly regardless of what I do it's
hedum in frusta concerperet nihil prorsus ex quo illud facio
cool yeah it's like the endless patience
yeah sicut frigus est infinita patientia
that they have they lost as long as
se habent ut non amissa modo
their battery right or that
Pugna ad dexteram neque
yeah yeah they can be plugged in a
yeah yeah possunt esse in SUPERGESTUS
laptop with motors and sense yeah now
laptop in motoribus et nunc sensum yeah
that's perfect no I mean as far as in
quod nemo perfectus sit usque ut in me
the classroom are they pretty like
Curabitur ut sunt fere
hearty because kids are kind of crazy
eo animo genus rabidus haedi
sometimes kids are kids and you know
haedos autem haedos aliquando et vos scitis
with that I mean one of the important
est quia intelliguntur qui ex amet
things that we offer to schools is a
quae tibi offerimus est scholarum
worry-free warranty so no matter what
praestat ut fatigo liberum, quod nulla res
happens you know we'll take care of you
fit enim scis tibi cura de vobis
and you know there won't be like crazy
et tu scis enim non erit similis rabidus
expenses to fix them great I mean we had
contemplantibus nobis hoc magnas expensas
kids that making the robot accidentally
accidit autem ut metus robot
walking off the edge of the table and
off in ore gladii, et ambulans in mensa
you know we got broken robots and in a
frangitur inque obtinuit scitis robots
very bad shape but that's okay I mean
formam bene dico quod pessimae
kids are kids
haedos autem haedos
and I this is part of the learning and
Et haec pars doctrinae
we want them to be able to experience
Nos volo ut esse potest experiri
and to experiment with with things and
et cum omnia experiri
figure out you know what went wrong and
et vos instar sicco quid abiit iniuriam
you know how would I make it better next
an nescibas quam eius esset, non facere bonum proximo
thing that's how we learn mm-hmm now how
ut aliquid discimus, quod suus 'iam mm hmm, how
easy is it to implant like the actual
facile est ut ipsam implantandi
education for the teachers because
educationem doctores, ad quod
you'll have to teach the teachers how to
youll 'have ut doceat quam scribarum
teach the kids right or do they do they
doce iustum accumsan vel faciunt
need some sort of special training as
opus est aliqua speciali institutione generis
far as bringing a robot that's a great
quatenus id haud magnum robot
question I mean we don't expect you know
dico tibi non arbitror quaestio
math teachers or literacy teachers you
math doctoribus vel magistris literacy
have to become PhD in robotics just in
et facti sunt solutae orationis apud sicut robotics
order to work with these kind of tools
instrumenta ad opus huiusmodi
so what we are doing is we are making
Quid ergo facimus facis
the the you know control and the
Scitis autem et vos, et control
accessibility but the access you know to
scitis autem accessum ad accessibility
the to the robot very very simple so as
in robot est ipsum simplex, ut sic
I mentioned earlier you can either
Ut iam est dictum vel vos can
control the robots from a web browser so
control robots ut a pasco telam
for example you know let's take another
exempli gratia lets scitis ut alius
math example if you wanted a robot to
exempli gratia, si volo tecum est a robot math
walk on a grid and wonder what you walk
Miror quod ambulare et ambulare in malesuada euismod
to let's say on the great - like a
lets 'narro ut ex magno - tamquam
two-by-two or whatever it is they need
sive ab bis duo esse necessaria
to figure out what's the angle that or
ut instar sicco quis suus 'seu anguli,
what need to turn it and how farther or
et quam ulterius pergere aut quid necesse est vertere
it needs to to walk so they can just set
sed opus ad ambulare possint et sicut profecti sunt
these two parameters on the on the web
binis ad ambitum web
browser heat go and the robot can go so
pasco ad calorem, et sic ibis robot possum
the teachers don't need to understand
Cum magistris scholarum, non opus est intelligere,
anything about robot Peter science and
robot aliquid de scientia et Petri
programming and everything right each
programmatio et honesta quaeque
math so this is one way
et hoc modo est math
the other way is using the very easy
aliter utitur facillimum
drag-and-drop interface basically you
et gutta, plerumque interface drag
know I want the robot to stand up I'll
Volo scio est a robot Et stabit
drag a box which is stand up box and you
quae est arca archa et stabit in longum differentur
know hit play and they're all it will
Omnes scire hit fabula, et tu eam faciet
stand up I don't need to program all of
consurge ad propositum opus non omnes
that to consider you know the motion and
considerans enim scitis quod in hoc motu
the center of mass center of gravity
centrum gravitatis in centro inertiae
where it is and these kind of things
ubi haec talia
that are all hidden from the teacher
quae omnia latent magister
yeah it sounds very it sounds very
Yeah sonat ipsa sonat ipsum
multi-layered as far as the level of the
Nunc autem multi usque gradum
education that's required in order to
quod suus 'requiritur ut educatione
achieve what you're looking to do so
consequi id quod petebas
what would kind of the age span be of
spatium tali tempore futurum sit in
like we're really focusing on on now the
re vera amo erant 'iam in focusing in
robot that we see on the screen today
ut hodie videmus in screen robot
what would be the age I mean it must be
in hoc saeculo necesse esset
as I get better at it so we have the
ita ut ad meliorem quam habemus
programs we develop programs from
ut develop progressio, a progressio
kindergarten all the way to college
Donec omnes ad collegium
level again it's not really you know age
item gradu et suus 'non realiter aetate scitis
restricted or something like that what's
aut sicut aliquid, quod suus 'non limitatur
you know has to be age appropriate is
noveris oportet quod habeat aetatem esse
the content and what we are teaching
qua contentus est atque erudimus
them so for example in the elementary
ita ut in elementis
school we are teaching them a
schola doces nos et illos
storytelling which is one of the skills
quam gravida feugiat condimentum est ad artes
that students are using today with you
ut alumni uti hodie tecum sunt,
know very short tweets or snapchats at
Nescio an snapchats tweets brevissimo tempore
that you know no one cares anymore about
ut nemo curat ultra dixerunt novimus
like spelling correctly right because
sicut rectum recto spelling
great become gr and the number-8 right
et facti sunt magno numero gr-VIII recta
and these kind of things so you know we
et huiusmodi rebus scitis
teach them you know how to create a
docere illos vos scitis quomodo creare
story and how to write a story and how
et quomodo fabula fabulam et quomodo scribere
to make this robot stand up and tell the
robot facere stare nuntians
stor reel sound effects and with motion
motus et sonus effectus et turbabuntur stor
and all of that and this is a way more
id quod omnes quodammodo
engaging you know a way to teach this
dimicandi facta est docere viam scitis
kind of subjects to students and it's
genus rerum studiosis suus
much more rewarding than you know
Scitis quam multa alia retribuendo
writing a 500 word essay you know Sen
scribo vobis quia verbum temptant per D inter Sen
submitted by Friday or else oh this is
O Veneris aut aliud subjuncta est
lovely a huge big thank you this means
pulchra ingens laudis magna vobis hoc modo
that you'll be teaching generations like
quia amo te in generationibus docere
to use proper punctuation and it's a
uti interpunctione et suus 'a propriis
good start right so then the question
Tum satus bonum justum
comes up I mean Jeff Weston isn't here
Ego hic non intelliguntur sunt Jeff est Weston '
with us tonight but I know that if he
hac nocte nobiscum sed ut si novi
was he'd be on the edge of a seat going
Euntes autem fore sedem super ripam
but but but are they going to take over
Illi vero non nisi acciperet
no jobs no there
non jobs sine est
hands are robots eventually going you
Tandem vado manus robots
know is the goal to to replace teachers
quia est finis, ad reponere teachers
here or what what's happening so the
aut quid hic sic fieri, quod suus '
goal is not to replace teachers and you
et magistris non est finis reponere
know these are not going to take any
non enim sciunt quicquam
jobs if I told the goal is to augment
si ad jobs qui finis est addere
the teacher and you provide more tools
et plura instrumenta magister providere
to engage 21st century learners right I
Saeculum 21 iustum pugnae discentibus
mean well I think I feel like there is
Ego quoque sentio amo is est medium
sometimes but in my life when I was
sed numquam in vita mea, cum essem
learning I would need extra time with a
cognita opus ut cum tempus subsicivum
task to actually grasp it but mostly
ceterum magna ex parte ad opus esse possit id capere,
math tasks but that a teacher just
sed quod tantum munia math magister
didn't have the time to give me so then
Itaque mihi non tempus
this could be you sort of in a special
Hoc autem esse apud vos modo peculiari
education or enhanced education
educatione et educationem decorarat atque auxerat,
situation as well where I mean that
in quo statu etiam intelliguntur, quae dico
robot could be dedicated to that kid
Hircus autem dicatum esse robot
in a time when the teacher needed to
per tempus quando opus est magister
focus on the rest of the classroom as a
Reliqua focus in Curabitur aliquet ultricies sicut
whole right yeah definitely we have that
totum jus quod habemus certum Yeah
as part of our program it's basically
sicut pars nostrae progressio quod suus 'basically
for oh you can call it remedial you know
Nam quis ipsum remedia scire possis
intervention so if someone needs an
ut si interventum eget
extra you know attention they can
non possumus extra operam scitis
actually get it with the robot so here
non vere adepto et hic cum robot
is the activity makes the robot do X it
hoc actio X robot est qui faciat ea
doesn't really matter what and by
et quod realiter non refert
working on that the students get firstly
ut alumni imprimis opus in eo
hands-on experience writing second they
secundam scribo ad manus-in experientia,
get the chance to learn at their own
ut in casu discere suis
pace with the tools that they care about
ipsi curo ut instrumenta cum pace
it because equations on the board don't
quia in illa aequatione non tabula
work they never work today in their
opus autem suum non operatur hodie
hands you know it will never work
manibus operari non scitis
mm-hmm yeah way way to keep their
Sic yeah, hmm mm iter suum
attention with something that's modern
operam ad quod aliquid modern
and edgy and fun and cool be a fun
Et erit pendens, ut refrigeret et fun fun
detention tool like you are not allowed
tu detention tamquam instrumentum non licet
to leave the classroom until you teach
Curabitur aliquet ultricies excedere dum docent,
the robot how to properly say this
quam recte dixeris in robot est
sentence so how say in the statuses
et dices ad damnationem status quo
spell it correctly because if you want
recte quaeris quod si eam spargant
spell it correctly
bene eam spargant
the robot can pronounce it correctly
pronuntio quod in robot possum recte
right trouble okay okay yeah no that
qui nihil juris tribulationis okay okay yeah
makes sense that makes total sense hey
heu, quae facit sensum sensum facit summa
we're talking with a lad in bar and he
erant loquentes cum puero, et vectes
is the CEO at robot lab you can find
CEO est a robot Lab vos can reperio
them at robot lab dot-com find out all
Lab eos in dot com-robot reperire ex omnibus
about what they're doing in the
de quo in discis
education sector
educationem sector
if you have questions join us in the
si habetis quaestiones iungere nobis ad
live chat room category five on freenode
Vivamus chat cubiculum in genus quinque freenode
or if you're watching this after the
aut, si tibi post vigilantes hoc
fact of course you can comment below and
quod utique non potest, et sub commento
we'll extend those questions as well can
te potest etiam quaestiones illae non extend
you make them say something anything
et dabo tibi aliquid dicere quod
even just introduce themselves I heard a
inducere sibi sicut et ego audivi
voice earlier when he was saying his IP
cum esset ante vocem suam dicentes IP
address right unfortunately say oh okay
o bene quod valde dolendum jus dicere address
so I couldn't connect them right now for
ut non iam ad coniungere illis
a chat but yes they can definitely say
et sic potest certus dicere quod sit chat
they can definitely talk they can
non possum dicere pro certo posse
definitely interact okay and now my next
et nunc bene penitus certe altera
questions that then is could it happen
ergo potuit fieri quaestiones
in any language are they easy to program
non est facilis in lingua enim progressio
say as a French learning tool in an
dico quod doctrina instrumentum per Gallicus
English classroom so they support 27
XXVII, sic eos support anglicus Curabitur aliquet ultricies
languages there is actually a cappella
Linguae est actu a cappella
if you're familiar with this voice
nota si vestri 'in hanc vocem,
engine embedded in the operating system
engine embedded in operating ratio
so the robot can both speak and
robot possum dicere quod sic tam
understand 27 languages so that's
XXVII, ita quod intelligere linguis:
definitely possible again we're looking
item erant 'vultus fieri potest
they're looking at now a lot but can you
ipsi erant 'vultus procul multus sed nunc vos can
tell us a little bit about the
dic paululum de
specifications of the robot that we see
cubits videmus quod in robot
here I mean it looks like they're
hic intelliguntur qui vultus amo non sis
attentive they're looking around is that
suspensus est, quod ipsi erant 'vultus circuitu
just head movement or they actually
sicut motus caput et non in actu,
taken pictures what's going on here so
quid hic sic suus 'iens die capta imaginibus
what's going on here is this we have
in quo habemus hic est, quod suus 'iens
four microphones around the head so the
Sic quatuor mikrofonu gyrum capitii textilem
robot is trying to localize the source
robot est fons conatur languages
of sound as I'm talking so if for
Si enim sic loqueris ad me et sana
example you know there is some echo in
exempli gratia est quaedam imaginem scitis
this room so it's a little bit confusing
hic locus tam exigua suus 'turbatio
for him but it's basically trying to you
illi tamen suus 'trying basically vobis
know close on the only coordinates of
proxima scitis unicum coordinatae
the speaker and give this a human you
speaker et in hoc non humanum est
know natural feel that I'm looking at
quia natura sentiunt, ut ad me?
you when I'm talking to you right we
Im 'non rectum ad te, quando tibi loqueris
don't want robots that are like yes what
robots, qui non vis ut id quod sic;
do you want right yeah yeah
Vis ius yeah yeah
looking at ceiling so we have four
Itaque quattuor vultus laquearia
microphones around the head we have two
microphones circum caput duorum habemus,
cameras this is the top camera over here
Vestibulum diam est summa huc
picture it over there is basically
adumbravimus illic est basically
looking forward and the bottom one looks
spectat et spectare deorsum
down towards the legs so we can detect
usque ad pedes, sic nos deprehendere
obstacles and you know places where the
locis, ubi impedimenta et scitis
robot shouldn't go we have inside
ne intra nos robot
and we have a full computer Intel Atom
et habere plenum computatrum Pentium
1.6 gigahertz a gigabyte of RAM I mean
Gigahertz 1.6 of RAM ut sit in gigabyte
you know computer for you know for
scio enim quia tu nosti computatrum
anything that we want we have a network
quid vis, ut nos a network
port on the back just like on the matrix
sicut ad matricem in portu
man yeah I mean here we go so that's why
memini quid hominem dico ut eamus hinc
he's motionless in his spine yeah i
quod est in concursu quieti spina yeah I.
suspended the motion because I don't
quia non est motus suspensus
want him to like you know right right
sicut scitis iustum rectum vult eum
but they are fully wireless as well you
sunt tibi bene et plene sicut wireless
know Wi-Fi is no way to go with this
Wi-FI iter hoc non scire
kind of robots the eyes are actually
quaedam etiam oculi robots
infrared sensors so they orbit cannot
ultrarubrum sensoriis non ita orbitae
turn on and off like TVs air
conversus in TV aeris ut quod off
conditioners or DVDs or has a remote
aut non est remote conditioners Books
control we have a sonic sensor gyro
GENIUS habemus potestatem gyro sensorem
accelerometer and decked and sensors of
constrata et in sensoriis et accelerometer
the robot can sense when when we touch
Cum tangere sentit cum robot quod potest,
it so it's pretty pretty advanced Robert
satis provectus est ut suus 'pulchellus Robert
we have 25 motors around the body and
XXV circa nos habemus corpus et motoribus,
are they full they're fully articulating
quod plene consentiat pars dimidio erant plenae sunt
I presume they they can move around and
Credo quod possint circum
and interact with their environment
cum nulla penitus
autonomous Lee autonomously yeah if you
Lee autonoma ratione, si sui iuris, de yeah
load the program on the robot you can
load de robot progressio vos can
just you know cause your computer let it
sicut scitis computatrum tuum faciam illud
run the program runs on the computer
fugit a computer progressio currere
which is with motors and sensors right
bonum quod est motor et sensoriis
that's great I feel like the children
quod sentio valde filios
like I two nephews that have autism
ut faciam ex eis nepotes duo quae habent autism
I feel like robots like this would be
EGO sentio amo robots sic esset,
great to teach some social skills even
pars magna socialis solers et docere
as far as eye contact and I mean if
quod si oculus contactus sit, et usque
these if these robots are looking at me
si quaeritis me isti sunt robots
when I'm talking but if I'm not looking
Im 'non loquitur nisi quod, si Im' vultus
at you when I'm talking like if I'm not
quando locuti estis ad me nisi ut non sum
looking at the robot when I'm talking
bellus cum Im 'in robot loquentes
maybe it doesn't get what I'm saying
id quod maybe Im 'non dicens
right like in my in the program and
sicut in dextera mea, et progressio
there's no are there's no intimidation
Ibi suus 'illic' nullum esse sine denuntiatione armorum terreret
factor they're speaking to one of these
non es factor loquebatur unus ex illis
so you're teaching effective
et tu doces effective
communication yeah and you actually test
yeah, et eris aut subiciemur test communicationis
a very important point here there is a
Hic est a puncto valde sit amet
program for you know to help
progressio iuvo vos scitis
autism treatment if quality treatment
qualis si autism curatio curatio
the first one the autism spectrum is
primum ad autism spectrum est
very well yeah but especially in the
sed maxime bene memini
emotions and in the detection detection
et palam facti motus deprehensio
of like human interaction throats are
sicut de humano consortio est guttur
awesome and the reason is this is out of
et hoc ex causa est terribilis
a research from Notre Dame University
a investigationis University de Notre
the reason is that the autistic kids are
quod ratio autistic haedi
very intimidated but by all the
sed omnibus valde perterriti
different you know levels of
tu scis diversis gradibus
communication that we have as human
Sicut enim homo, ut communicationis
beings we have different tone of voice
quas nos habemus ex diversis sono vocis
we have you know bad emotion we use a
scire autem vos utor a concitatione affecti simus nos malum
lot of nonverbal communication which is
qui communicationis multum nonverbal
like you know a sensory overload for
tu scis quia amo sensitiva cultro
them it's in yeah they just prefer to
Gaudete in illa suus 'iustus antepono
shut down because it's too much for them
Quia nimis clausa hos
with robots it's very precise I mean the
cum exactissimam illud dico robots
motion will be exactly the same motion
erit motus exacte eundem motum,
it would be hundred times in the
foret in centuplo
thousands bar right the tone of voice
bar ius ad milia ex sono vocis
will be exactly the same tone of voice
Erit autem prorsus eodem sono vocis
and it gives the kids the confidence in
Fiduciam dabit accumsan
what's going to happen so they are
ideo quid futurum
opening to listen to actually be able to
ut ipse bene poterit foramen audire
digest the information that being passed
Transierunt illa notitia quae digerunt,
to them and by working with this kind of
huiusmodi negotio illis
you know robots and this kind of program
robots tu scis et quaedam progressio
we've seen amazing amazing changes in
vidi enim mirabile est mirabile in commutationes
kids and parents lives there are kids
vivit enim pellentesque pellentesque parentesque
that started to communicate after
coepi cum eo communicare,
working on these robots I mean some
His quidam hoc opus robots
experts wouldn't even talk to them and
peritorum et non loqui
after you know sometimes working with
post te scire opus ex numquam
that they can actually communicate a
communicate non possunt hoc ipsum sit
connection to talk which is awesome
quam terribilis sit in nexu Disputatio
and I would imagine just the
hoc cogitet et iustus
programmability and being able to do
et quod maxime placeat facere programmability
more than just play with it and actually
magis quam iustus ludere cum eo tendens, ultro
learn you know I think about learning
discat cogitare de doctrina non scitis
how it works and programming it and and
et quomodo opera et programming
in telling it hey do this and having it
Nullam et ipsum habere hoc praedicere
do that yeah would just be incredibly
yeah, qui non esset iustus exsisto incredibiliter
exciting yeah we have a professor at
yeah excitando habemus professor procul
Northridge California State University
Northridge rei publicae Universitatis California
in North Northridge that actually made
ut etiam in in North Northridge
the robot as a training tool for you
quod in robot disciplina tool pro vobis
know basically teachers for forty
scio plerumque magistros quadraginta
stickies so the robot is is the sticky
stickies in robot est ut sit amet
so you throwing a tantrum you know the
tu nosti tantrum coniectis
teacher needs to you know relax the
magister indiget ad relaxat et scitis
robot so this is the
et hoc est robot
Wow seen seem late you know the kid is
Curabitur non potest videri nuper tibi hedum
an example right so that's a completely
Habemus exemplum quod omnino
opposite end of the education factor of
diversissimam elementum educationis
the robot it's so cool yeah yeah is a
sic suus 'in robot est refrigescant yeah yeah
tool and there's a platform it can do so
et illic 'a tool facere possit platform
many things it I always say we are
multa autem dico non semper sunt,
limited by our imagination I'm excited
limited ab imaginatione nostra non sum excitatur
to be around in this time of life like
circa quod tempus vitae
robots are coming to us in you know all
scis omne venturus est nobis in robots
these exciting new ways and this is my
haec via, et hoc est novum excitando
favorite so far I'll tell you I'm going
Et ventus quatenus sic Im 'iens dicere
I'm going together
Eo simul
hey hey lad what is you know what do you
heus heus tu scis quod tu puer parvulus enim est
see as being kind of the next step in
Sequitur videre quale sit in
robotics in education when it comes to
Robotics adveniens educationis
what you're doing with robot lab what's
Quid tibi discis quid ad robot Lab
what's coming up so we're not using only
Quod suus 'sic venire in tantum, erant' non usura
humanoid robots we're using many other
humanoid robots erant 'usura aliis multis
different products from quad copters to
est alia res de quad copters
Rovers to I'm sure you're familiar with
Nota Im 'certus ut vestri' cum rovers
the bb-8 the fewer one so we're using
VIII-b ad a paucioribus uti est ita et nos
different yes I robots and I would say
et quod sic dicat et alia robots
the the next wave will be more like
in proximo sit similior et fluctus
specialized you know tools now well
scis iam tum instrumenta specialized
these these are great and there are
Haec verba sunt magnae
suits sincerely and seriously great
Magna decet vere graviterque
tools
instrumenta
yeah they you know might be overkill for
ipsi enim scitis esse memini overkill
some tasks for some you know something
quaedam exercere diebus aliquot novi aliquid vobis
that we want to to teach our kids so
quod kids ut nos docere volunt
there will be different robots that will
Erit autem quod alia robots
be able to do different things probably
quae non alia esse poterit verisimile
better than what human and robot can do
et quod homo potest facere melius robot
I mean like as mean we can run up to a
Et quod medium sit ut possimus usque ad currere
certain speed for money if we need to go
celeritas aliqua, si opus est argentum et vade
faster we'll take a car we won't you
Nos autem non sumus citius youll accipere a car
know improve our running capabilities
scio amplio nostra cursus elit
200 miles per hour right right so these
Hi CC milia stundā right
kind of things we just keep seeing over
quaedam autem sunt in tantum ut cum
and over again
et hostium est suffocatus
and this robot can't fly and if you want
et robot possum fugere, et si vis
to take aerial photos and want to teach
ut velis docere, et aeria photos
you know kids about you know areas and
tu scis te scire locis et haedos
range and so on
ita rhoncus
it's much easier today to the quadcopter
Hodie suus 'facillimus quantum ad quadcopter
so you know this is how we are working
quomodo ergo tu scis hoc quod operatus es nobis
in in our company we're trying to find
in comitatu erant 'trying ut reperio in
the best fit you know the best product -
optimus uber idoneum optime nosti -
the best sub - the subject that we want
sub optimos - subiectum quod volunt
to teach and how do you see you know
docere quid vos videtis et scitis
what's the difference in the kind of
Quid interest quali
quad copters that robot lab is working
Lab opus est, ut robot quad copters
with versus you know
et versus scitis
the kind that I fly to shoot my video
quae volant in genere meo, ut mitterent video
exactly the same so they do they have
prorsus similiter habent et faciunt
just the same kind of thing and just
atque idem genere
learning how to it's the same yourself
idem ipse est discat
yeah it's same thing but what we teach
Quid est hoc memini docemus
is not how to fly them is we're using
non modo fugere eos, qui erant 'usura
them for example we have a program that
exempli gratia ea habemus, quae progressio
uses the quadcopter to teach elementary
utitur enim quadcopter docere elementa exordii
students about shapes so we are flying
alumni circa nos volantes sic shapes
that we let the teacher flight above the
qui docet nos super fuga
school yeah we go do they you know play
ipsi enim scitis fabula ludum ire debemus yeah
and just like right above the schools
Et sicut recta super scholarum
and they take a video of that and then
et accipies illius et video
they go back to the classroom and they
Curabitur et non revertens
need to analyze you know what are the
analyze quid opus est tibi
ships you know the school is built from
Naves nosti disciplinam struitur
sonic wave squares or triangles we have
GENIUS aut fluctus angulis triangulorum, ut
circles and so on and then they go in
et sic ingredietur circulorum
and do the measurements so if one edge
et sic dimensiones ora
of you know our gymnasium as an example
scitis autem et vos nostra, in gymnasium includi iuberent, ut exempli gratia
yeah okay it's a hundred foot okay
pedites bene memini bene suus
what's the area okay and just kind of
Bene iustum spatium quale quid
one out so you're doing the same you're
et tu agis hic unus
doing exactly the same stuff that we all
omnes eadem domi quae agis
learned in school but you're just saying
in schola didici, sed dicentem iustus es
oh here's a way to keep the kids excited
hic haedos proh dolor ita ut
about it right that's right because this
Haec circa ius, ut quod iustum est
is a little different generation that's
quod parum differt a generatione
the whole thing when when was the last
Cùm autem ultimus orbis
time that you used you know I don't know
tempus usus vobis nescio vos scitis
the angle my Gurion theorem I use that
Gu- conclusio mea, quod uti anguli
one every day maybe it's okay if you
unus dies bene si forte
know you look at your school and you
scio te respice in ludum et
actually need to change the walls or to
actually postulo ut immutare aut muros
do something how much pain do you need
quanto vos postulo ut aliquid doloris
okay so let's measure that and it's not
et sic non est mensura purus
just like a you know an assumption or
sicut scitis quod in assumptione aut
whatever let's take a tool a cool tool
ferrum ferro nibh id fiat scriptor
that really engages the student and use
re usum et, quae movet discipulus
that in order to help them to measure to
in quo metimur, ut adiuvent eos
help them you know to practice the
et auxiliatus sum tibi scire faceret
skills that you want them to study I
artes illas enim vis studere me
wish I grew up at one of your schools
Utinam modo tuis studia adolevisset
man because I learned with the yardstick
didici quod homo cum in mensura
yes well a lad in bar is from robot lab
quod sic tam puer unus talea per, est a robot Lab
calm please check them out and a lab it
sed quiescere velit coercet et Lab
is such a pleasure having you here on
quod tam delectatio habent hic est
the show thanks for bringing now and now
sollicitus intentusque iam nunc et gratias ago ostendo
along with you today as well they're
per te hodie ut sis ut bene
super cool cool thank you thanks for
gratias ago tibi, quia frigus frigus Super
having me and Cheers did you notice the
et tu animadverto quod habent Inscription
bots behind us my son Zack loaned us his
PDF Zack creditae, nobis post nos recensiones minores in filium meum
two robots because he knew that we were
duo robots quia sciebant essemus
talking about robots tonight so I
robots ut de hac nocte
thought oh it would be really cool if
O vere frigus esse putavit, si hoc esset,
Dad were to put my robots
Ut esset pater meus posuit robots
on the show so thank you to Zack for
ad spectaculum tam gratias ago tibi, quia ut Zack
loaning us those tonight right and even
sed hac dextra nobis faenus
when he was here playing with them and
cum hic esset per ludens eos
he was so engaged with them bro BOTS do
bro automata facere cum proelium uenire
something two kids and two adults that I
duos haedos et adultis duo aliquid, quod
have never seen with anything else like
quia nunquam visum est aliud simile
they just are so much fun I think
iusta sunt fun ut tantum puto
especially as you get into autonomous
praecipue quod in tempore sui iuris,
activities that excites me the robot up
quia actiones sunt robot incitat me
here that can program it right from the
Hic propositum qui a dextris eius
controller so he sets a program and then
moderatorem et sic ponit rationem
he pushed his play and it does all the
et proiecit eum non ludere omnes
things that he programmed it to do and
quae facturus est programma
he loves it not yeah it's I mean these
Non memini me dilexit eam sibi
are we saw now and now is like
qui iam nunc et vidimus similis
cutting-edge the best it's got that
suus 'got ut sectione-ore optimis
Intel processor in it in its brains
Intel processus in in cerebris,
smart stuff fast stuff and able to do a
dolor supellectilem ieiunium et potest facere a supellectilem
lot of things that's powered by Debian
multum per debian quod suus 'powered
which we love you love this it would be
quod si hoc amas
such a handy tool on so many levels even
tam habilis ad instrumentum, sic et multiplicibus gradibus procedere
I was thinking homeschooling because
Food putabam quod
some parents are really into
parentes qui in aliqua re
homeschooling their kids if she really
si vere sua haedos homeschooling
that robot they just sit around drinking
quod non solum sit circa robot bibens
whiskey I'm just saying it would it
Im 'iustus non esset cupam dicens
would be helpful to keep an ongoing
ut perinde esset utile
because you have kids are different ages
habentem aetatum haedi
right so you're homeschooling say three
et dextera tribus dicam tibi homeschooling
kids you can have an ongoing lesson with
possis habere haedos ongoing castigavit
one child while you're having a
dum alter puer es habens
breakaway lesson with the other two
alterum breakaway castigavit
right I like it
ius tibi placet
it's like increase in your stats I'm a
est sicut civitas incremento in me est
little cute little robot very cool stuff
bellus paulo minus materia frigidissima robot
you
vos